Mss.649.962.Sh6m
American Philosophical Society
Real property surveys, 1741-1831, [n.d.]
Mss.649.962.Sh6m
American Philosophical Society
0.25 Linear feet 59 items
59 items.
These are maps of various pieces of property in the Southwark division of Philadelphia which belonged to certain members of the Shippen family. They include maps taken, in part, from Philadelphia City records, as well as up-to-the-minute surveys done when the property was sold or subdivided. There are names of purchasers in some cases, showing which lots were acquired. There are also drawings of tracts of lands near roads or water and of estates of persons other than the Shippens.
Oversize 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased from Carmen Valentino ($1620.00) and accessioned, 12/29/1983 (1983 1686m).
Biographical/Historical note
The Shippen family had a long history of involvement in Philadelphia politics, business, medicine, and science. They owned much property south of the old section of the city of Philadelphia.
Burd, Edward Shippen, 1779-1848; Coombs, D.; Duché, Anthony, -- fl. 1775.; Duché, John; Flower, John; Flower, William G.; Garrigues, Mary; Gloria Dei Church (Philadelphia, Pa.); Graeme, John; Groves, D.; Hills, John, -- fl. 1777?-1817.; Howell, Reading, 1743-1827; McCall, Lawrence; McGoffin, John; Morris, Israel, 1741-1806; Morris, Samuel, 1734-1812; Scull, William, fl. 1765; Shippen family.; Shippen, Edward,1729-1806.; Shippen, Joseph,1706-1793.; Shippen, William, 1712-1801; Camden County (N.J.) -- Maps.; Church buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Maps.; Maps.; Real property -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- Maps.; Surveys (land).
- Plan of subdivision recorded with release of Edward Shippen to Joseph Shippen, Philadelphia, Second Street to Delaware River, 1 August 1741; 1; 1 map, 27.5 x 36.5 cm
  Other Finding Aids note
  Realms of Gold, 46 (1).
- Partition of land belonging to Duche, Knowles, Parham, and Cox, 16 August 1744; 2; 1 map, 30.5 x 48 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (2).
- Partition of land of Arkton(?) and wife, and Samuel Wheeler, 3 September 1750; 3; 1 map, 30.5 x 48.5 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (3).
- Partition of the Shippen estate on South S[treet], 11 October 1756; 4; 1 map, 33 x 49.5 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (4).
- Lot of Dr. William Shippen on east side of Shippen's Lane, 18 August 1762; 5; 1 map, 20.5 x 33.5 cm; Scull, William, fl. 1765
  Realms of Gold, 46 (5).
- Land on the Delaware River fronting League Island, 22 July 1769; 6; 1 map, 30 x 40 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (6).
- Mary Garrigue's estate [on Queen Street], 1773; 7; 1 map, 35.4 x 52.5 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (7).
- Partition of N. Pryors estate, 11 March 1774; 8; 1 map, 20.4 x 34.2 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (8).
- Plan of 64 acres... called Solitude, the property of Samuel and Israel Morris, 1788; 9; 1 map, 38.5 x 84 cm; Hills, John, surveyor
  Realms of Gold, 46 (9).
- Road to be opened from Grays Ferry, 3 November 1792; 10; 1 map, 38.4 x 31.3 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (10).
- Survey of the property of John Duche, 14 November 1794; 11; 1 map, 22.4 x 19.4 cm; Duché, John
  Realms of Gold, 46 (11).
- Lands of Bankson estate, May Road, Turner's Lane, and Moyamensing Road, 5 November 1795; 12; 1 map, 30.5 x 48.5 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (12).
- Hardie's property, Pass[yunk] Road and Oak Street, 1799; 13; 1 map, 25.6 x 21.3 cm
  Scope and Contents note
  Colored.
  Realms of Gold, 46 (13).
- Lot covering square in Philadelphia between Fourth and Fifth Streets and Shippen Street, 4 August 1802; 14; 1 map, 40 x 34 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (14).
- Plots on Shippens Lane: Plots on Catharine Street, 6 October 1815; 15; 1 map, 31 x 47 cm
  On the reverse is: Drafts of plots, n.d.
  Realms of Gold, 46 (15).
- The lots on the south side of Cedar Street [with names of Edward, William, and Joseph Shippen as owners], 1816; 16; 1 map, 19 x 53 cm; Groves, D.
  Realms of Gold, 46 (17).
- Lots on south side of Cedar Street with names of Edward, William, and Joseph Shippen as owners, Circa 1816; 17; 1 map, 25 x 38.5 cm; Groves, D.
  Realms of Gold, 46 (16).
- Survey of "late Dr. Shippen's estate", 28 April 1825; 18; 1 map, 20 x 24.8 cm
  Realms of Gold, 46 (18).
- Tracts fronting on the Delaware River, 17 May 1831 - 21 May 1831; 19; 1 map, 42.3 x 36.3 cm; Coombs, D.
  Realms of Gold, 46 (19).
- Draft of a survey, n.d.; 20; 1 map, 26.8 x 38.3 cm
  Related Archival Materials note
  See also #42.
- Draft of a survey, n.d.; 21; 1 map, 17.2 x 38.6 cm
  See also #43.
- Draft of city lots, n.d.; 22; 1 map, 37.4 x 52.8 cm
  See also #57.
- Division of land between Fifth and Seventh Streets on Shippen Street, 23; 1 map, 30.5 x 48 cm
- Drafts of plots, n.d.; 24; 1 map, 31 x 47 cm
  See also #15.
- Estate of William G. Flower, Christian Street, and Passyunk Road, 25; 1 map, 30.5 x 48.5 cm
  See also #51.
- Federal Street and Buck Road area, 26; 1 map, 21.6 x 27.2 cm
  Joins with item #28.
- Land near Little Holland Creek, 27; 1 map, 25.7 x 37.2 cm
  See also #41.
- Land on the road to Gray's Ferry, 28; 1 map, 21 x 54 cm
  Joins with item #26.
- Lots on German Street, 20 July 1774; 29; 1 map, 25.7 x 40.6 cm
- Lots on Queen and Catharine Streets, 30; 1 map, 35.4 x 52.5 cm
  See also #7.
- Lots sold by Francis Moore, n.d.; 31; 1 map, 19.5 x 21.7 cm
- Gray's Ferry Road area, n.d.; 32; 1 map, 26.4 x 42 cm
- Lands patent to Lawrence McCall and John Graeme, 33; 1 map, 23.3 x 25.3 cm
- Lots between Shippen and South Streets, 34; 1 map, 31.8 x 39.3 cm
- Lots between Swanson and Moyamensing Streets, 35; 1 map, 18.5 x 25.6 cm
- Lots on Fitzwater and Passyunk Road, 36; 1 map, 23.2 x 43.3 cm
  See also #37.
- Lots on Fitzwater and Passyunk Road, 37; 1 map, 23.2 x 43.3 cm
- Some Passyunk Road lots, n.d.; 38; 1 map, 31.3 x 38.5 cm
- Some property of Anthony Duche, n.d.; 39; 1 map, 31 x 40 cm
- Penrose partition, Catharine Street, n.d.; 40; 1 map, 24.6 x 38.6 cm
- Unidentified land, 41; 1 map, 25.7 x 37.2 cm
  See also #27.
- Unidentified property, n.d.; 42; 1 map, 30 x 40 cm
  See also #6.
- Meadow on Hall Creek bought by A. Noble, n.d.; 43; 1 map, 17.2 x 38.6 cm
  See also #21.
- Mifflin's partition, Second and Front Streets, 44; 1 map, 26.8 x 38.3 cm
  See also #20.
- Old Swedes Church area, n.d.; 45; 1 map, 27 x 33.5 cm
- Partition of Anthony Duche's estate, n.d.; 46; 1 map, 30.5 x 49 cm
  See also #58.
- Partition of estate of John Inglis; Christian Street and Passyunk Road, 47; 1 map, 24 x 54.5 cm
- Partition of Penrose and Hulbert and others, and Mariott's lands, Passyunk and Moyamensing Roads, 48; 1 map, 30.5 x 46 cm
- Property at Fifth and "Plumb" Streets, 49; 1 map, 31 x 21.2 cm
- Plan of ground belonging to the Heirs of John Flower, No. 1 Property of William G. Flower, 50; 1 map, 38.5 x 48 cm
- Rough draft of city plots, n.d.; 51; 1 map, 30.5 x 48.5 cm
  See also #25.
- Rough draft of city plots, n.d.; 52; 1 map, 30.5 x 48 cm
  See also #2.
- Shippen Street, centered between Cedar and "Plumb", 53; 1 map, 24.5 x 39.3 cm
- Shippen Street frontage from Penn Street to George Street, n.d.; 54; 1 map, 33 x 63.5 cm
- Southwark, generally, with Delaware River, n.d.; 55; 1 map, 55 x 46 cm
- Survey of various properties, n.d.; 56; 1 map, 21.5 x 37.9 cm
- Ten lots granted by Edward S. Burd to John McGoffin, n.d.; 57; 1 map, 37.4 x 52.8 cm
  See also #22.
- Two small outlines of plots, n.d.; 58; 1 map, 30.5 x 49 cm
  See also #46.
- Lots near Cedar and Seventh Streets, 59; 1 map, 31.8 x 38.5 cm